This exercise is for spinal extension.
Working the muscles in the back.
Go ahead and center your ball in front of your body and lean into the ball.
So, the ball should be just up above your pelvis.
Digging your hipbones into the ball.
Bring your hands to the back of your head.
Or, if you want, you can bring your hands out here.
Gently touching the back of your head.
Head is in line with the spine.
Take a nice inhale and exhale come back.
Closing the ribcage to protect your back.
Inhale.
Come forward to stretch out the back.
Exhale.
Come back.
Closing the ribcage.
Inhale.
Forward.
Exhale.
Back.
And, inhale.
Forward.
And, when you are done, go ahead and stretch over the ball.
Hug it.
Separating the scapula to release those muscles in your back.